<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quercus Coaching</title>
    <description>Create a life that you love.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 16:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 16:50:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coaching for carers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coaching is like a gym for the brain. It brings new perspective to a situation and supports people to find their own solutions and take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a previously full –time carer myself, I found that I had a lot of time to think, but felt that I couldn’t change anything about my situation. As a consequence, my thinking became more and more negative and brought me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation helped neither me nor the person I was caring for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend introduced me to coaching and I found that it opened the door to a new way of thinking. Coaching uses skilful questions to break up negative patterns of thinking, challenge assumptions and dispel the myths we tell ourselves  about ‘I can’t…..’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching focuses, not on the situation we are in, but on our perspective on that situation. When we explore our core values and find out what we are really committed to, then we re-discover the reasons why we are doing what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/IMG_1460.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ella&#39;s first image.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your top 3 values?&lt;/strong&gt; (Take out any values that you feel you ‘should’ have or you adopted because parents or an authority figure told you to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you express these values in your life? Who and what are you committed to? How do you measure your success? Is it in relation to your commitments or to other people’s expectations? What do you do that is not aligned to your values, and how much does this cost you in energy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much energy would be available to you if you lived a life aligned with your values ? How would your view of your current life change if your perspective came from the values at the heart of who you are?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching doesn’t have to be about taking on the world, instead, it’s about creating a worldview centred on your values and creating a life that you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Contacts page&lt;/a&gt; to sign up or to get in touch with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/01/17/coaching-for-carers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/01/17/coaching-for-carers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
