<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quercus Coaching</title>
    <description>Create a life that you love.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 16:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 16:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are you trying to squeeze more into an already full life?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you trying to squeeze more into an already full life?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever noticed that so many things that could improve your life involve adding … &lt;strong&gt;more?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; time in the gym/with the kids/meditating/jogging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; information about getting fit/healthy eating/how to succeed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; attention to your loved ones/the present moment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; action around career goals/marketing yourself/searching for The One.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in my experience, trying to put more into a cup which is already full just results in overflow. In our lives that can feel like overwhelm - resulting in less sleep, poor health, low self esteem, guilt and even shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are led to believe that if we only knew/did/had/were … (fill in the gap yourself) our lives would be perfect, and when we fail and end up feeling worse about ourselves – and less likely to try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the job of a coach is to help you empty the cup – review your life to look at what’s working and, in areas of your life which aren’t working, examine what you have been doing and what you have learnt about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of emptying the cup also involves discarding the ‘shoulds’ in your life so that you are left with &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; core values – the ones that get you up in the morning. These values will be reflected in what you are committed to in life and the strengths that get you through the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching can act like a knife to cut away everything that isn’t &lt;u&gt;you&lt;/u&gt; or aligned with &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; values. Clients experience a clarity of vision that can be exhilarating, liberating the energy trapped in previous failed attempts, to be redirected into the strengths that have already got you this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;For example&lt;/u&gt;, who wants to lose weight? How many times have you tried and how much energy have you expended on this? However, to ‘lose weight’ covers many different areas- e.g. how healthy you feel, your size, what you eat, your shape.
What would it be like to give up the idea of losing weight? How would it feel to be ok about the weight you are now? Notice how your body responds to that thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, what is it &lt;u&gt;specifically&lt;/u&gt; that you want?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To feel toned/fit into a size smaller?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To feel less out of breath?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To sleep better?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To give up coffee/sugar/alcohol/chocolate/smoking?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To have more energy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Choose one area&lt;/u&gt; and look at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when you have tried and failed - and what you said about yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what you think you ‘should’ do/be/have in this area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you gave up all the regrets/blame/sense of failure, what one step could you do today to give you a positive result in this area?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make it something that you enjoy, something that you are already good at or something that is aligned to a commitment you already have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are filled to the brim with knowledge, but knowledge isn’t enough until it works in the service of &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; values, &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; strengths and &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; commitments. 
Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/03/30/blog-march/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/03/30/blog-march/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coaching for carers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coaching is like a gym for the brain. It brings new perspective to a situation and supports people to find their own solutions and take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a previously full –time carer myself, I found that I had a lot of time to think, but felt that I couldn’t change anything about my situation. As a consequence, my thinking became more and more negative and brought me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation helped neither me nor the person I was caring for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend introduced me to coaching and I found that it opened the door to a new way of thinking. Coaching uses skilful questions to break up negative patterns of thinking, challenge assumptions and dispel the myths we tell ourselves  about ‘I can’t…..’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching focuses, not on the situation we are in, but on our perspective on that situation. When we explore our core values and find out what we are really committed to, then we re-discover the reasons why we are doing what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/IMG_1460.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ella&#39;s first image.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your top 3 values?&lt;/strong&gt; (Take out any values that you feel you ‘should’ have or you adopted because parents or an authority figure told you to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you express these values in your life? Who and what are you committed to? How do you measure your success? Is it in relation to your commitments or to other people’s expectations? What do you do that is not aligned to your values, and how much does this cost you in energy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much energy would be available to you if you lived a life aligned with your values ? How would your view of your current life change if your perspective came from the values at the heart of who you are?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching doesn’t have to be about taking on the world, instead, it’s about creating a worldview centred on your values and creating a life that you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Contacts page&lt;/a&gt; to sign up or to get in touch with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/01/17/coaching-for-carers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/01/17/coaching-for-carers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
