<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quercus Coaching</title>
    <description>Create a life that you love.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 22:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 22:35:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Struggling to achieve your goal?</title>
        <description>&lt;!--**Struggling to achieve your goal?**--&gt;

&lt;!--**How knowing your personality type can help you play to your strengths.**--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find your personality type, answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being with people
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;gives me energy,&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;tires me so I need time alone.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am motivated by
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;getting things done,&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;helping people with what they need to do.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broadly speaking, question 1. distinguishes the extroverts who get stimulatedby being with people, from introverts who need to rest after being withpeople.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question 2. separates people who are a) task focused and take pride in ticking off a To Do list from b) people who are people focused and measure their success by the responses from the people in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These broad generalisations (discovered by the psychologist William Moutlton Marston and later made into the DISC behaviour assessment tool) can be used to analyse how we can use the strengths of our personality types to achieve our goals more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, take the 4 different personality types and how they could use their personality strengths in relation to e.g. getting fit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type 1.&lt;/strong&gt; A task-focused extrovert is a natural leader and would rise to challenges - especially if it was up to them to show others the way. This personality type thrives on taking charge and getting things done -strategies that they could use would be to launch some sort of challenge to other members of their group e.g. a squash league at the gym; qualifying for a triathlon; improving on their personal best. These people thrive on finishing tasks, measuring their progress and healthy competition with others. As long as the outcome is largely within their control they will do their very best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type 2.&lt;/strong&gt; A task-focused introvert will also be motivated by measured goals, but they won&#39;t want to be in competition with others. Instead, their self-discipline and strong analytical skills mean that they work best by creating a routine. They are the sort of people who put gym time/exercise in their diary and do it religiously. They plan their shopping, pre-prepare meals, calorie-count, use heart monitors, keep food and exercise diaries and know exactly what works and doesn&#39;t work for them. Organisation skills are their strength, perfectionism is their downfall, but by creating a routine that supports them and a little wriggle room for the occasional lapse, they make steady and consistent gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type 3.&lt;/strong&gt; People-focused extrovert thrive in groups and with an audience. These charismatic people inspire others and live for praise and popularity. They are outgoing and persuasive and so can keep a group of people motivated. By sharing their ups and downs on e.g. social media, they avoid the loneliness of tackling their goal alone and unsupported. They will spend just as much time in classes as outside them, generating enthusiasm and bonding with the rest of the class. Any exercise that seems fun and where they can inspire others will be more successful for them. If you are a people-focused extrovert, try joining an exercise group on Instagram and upload your inspiring recipes and latest exercise triumphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type 4.&lt;/strong&gt; People-focused introverts work well in a supportive role. If they can find a colleague or friend who wants to exercise but needs a bit of a push, this type of personality will be your ideal &#39;gym-buddy&#39;. They are so loyal, they will never let you down. Also, they have great staying power and will be the people that complete the series of classes, never missing one. They can occur as quiet and shy and probably won&#39;t make the first move- so will let other personality types take the lead. If you are a people-focused introvert who hasn&#39;t yet been asked to &#39;dance&#39;, you can still use your strengths to set up an exercise routine at home, using home equipment, DVDs, videos etc. Due to your reflective nature, you may enjoy more interior-focussed styles of exercise e.g. yoga. Most of us are a combination of these personality types - with one style which tends to be dominant. Whilst these are only broad generalisations, they may help you work out new strategies that play on your strengths and also explain why some strategies don&#39;t work for you no matter how much effort you put 
into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out what style you think you are and try applying it to the current goals in your life - are you fully utilising the strengths of your personality to achieve these goals or are you trying to be someone else? What new options for action are now open to you? Have fun playing…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/08/08/blog-august/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/08/08/blog-august/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are your life goals all about numbers?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are your life goals all about numbers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you focusing on getting that pay rise/into a size 12/to 9 stone/8 hours sleep/ level 6 on the Cross Trainer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is life starting to sound like a To Do list with too much on it and too little time to do it all?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So often, we hear that coaching is about making SMART goals i.e. Specific, Measurable, Agreed upon, Realistic and Time Bound. But we can end up focusing on the action as a To Do, rather than the feelings and values that achieving this goal would bring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will you feel when you get that pay rise/dress size/sleep/level offitness/slimness? Let me guess.. happy? fulfilled? joyous? successful? valued? confident?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what about focusing on that feeling instead? For example, how can you build confidence/being valued/joyous/fulfilled/successful into your life right now, doing what you have to do anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of finding more things to do, change &lt;u&gt;how&lt;/u&gt; you are doing the things you already do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you want to feel fit/sleep better, how can you move more in a day? Become an analyst of your own life - what&#39;s in your calendar that you could add movement to? Getting to and from work/school/shops? Spending time with children/friends/your partner? Get creative about that feeling of being fit and mimic what a fit person would do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a pay rise would make you feel valued, where else could you cultivate an attitude of value? When you begin to see life through the prism of value, you start to not only value people/services/places, but also what you bring to the table - what would be missing if you weren&#39;t there? Where else in your life would you like to provide value? What could you do to value yourself more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we get hung up on a number, we lose the real goal i.e. &lt;u&gt;how we want to feel&lt;/u&gt; once we have achieved the goal. We lose our focus and creativity and become like a machine, hacking away doggedly to get to the number, only to find, guess what, that we can achieve the number and still not experience the feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many times have you thought and believed that your life would be so much better if you got that job/relationship/weight/dress size and found that, when you got it, you didn&#39;t feel any different or that the feeling didn&#39;t last or you even felt disappointed that it wasn&#39;t worth all the effort?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holding onto a number as a specific measure of your level of success in life is exhausting and will be frustrated by the way life constantly changes. Nothing stays static, and events will occur which sabotage your precious number - and then how will you feel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of fixed goals, &lt;u&gt;focus on the value or feeling that you want to create&lt;/u&gt; in your lives and start treading that path from Day 1 and keep walking with that as your intent, looking for any and every opportunity to express it as a way of life - not just another action on our To Do list.
Wishing you well on your journey….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/07/08/are_your_life_goals_all_about_numbers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/07/08/are_your_life_goals_all_about_numbers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are you sabotaging yourself?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you sabotaging yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start projects with the best intentions, then they fail and we claim that we didn’t know why… But if you really took the time to examine it, you would probably find one or more of the following culprits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.	Setting too big a goal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you trying to halve your calorie intake? Double the length of your run?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are creatures of habit. Good habits are beneficial activities that have become unconscious – we &lt;u&gt;don’t&lt;/u&gt; have to build the motivation to do them, in fact, we experience a nagging thought in the back of the mind when we don’t do them. However, habits create inertia for big changes – something that was unconscious now becomes conscious and involves more effort. It’s easier to adjust your action by 5-10% over 21 days and repeat, than try and make big shifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.	Setting a goal that’s not specific.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Improve my health’, ‘work on my relationship’ are not specific goals, and, consequently, you won’t know when you have achieved them. Without a sense of achievement, there is little motivation to continue the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Break your goal down into small, specific steps eg. ‘attend gym class on Wednesday morning’ or ‘go out with phones turned off, on Friday nights’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test each action to see which brings you nearer your goal, get inventive and celebrate your success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.	Focus on statistics rather than feelings.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you focusing on a number? A pay rise/ideal weight/bank balance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, what does the number mean to you? How will you feel when you have achieved it? What will it mean to the rest of your life and to the people around you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on a number can become a burden and sometimes achieving the number doesn’t give you the feeling you wanted. Instead, look at what that number would give you – a pay rise may mean for you that you are valued and being rewarded. What other actions can you take on to create this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.	Cutting out versus cutting down&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you trying to go ‘cold turkey’ and give up something e.g. sugar/alcohol/cigarettes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this activity give you e.g pleasure/relaxation/comfort? Look for replacements; would you get the same feeling from a bath/nap/walk outside/listening to music? If you focused on activity which gave you pleasure instead, would this reduce the likelihood of sabotage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out what your triggers are for this behaviour e.g. what mood are you in? who are you with? what are you doing? What plans could you make to avoid these triggers e.g. always having a healthy snack with you/buying smaller bottles of wine/packs of cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of going ‘cold turkey’, build in conscious attention to the activity – do it without distractions, almost like a meditation and feel the moment when you have had enough and stop –and throw away what’s left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start making an unconscious activity conscious so that you have a choice and celebrate all the small wins as the new behaviours become good habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.	Waiting for the motivation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Oliver Burkeman stated in The Guardian newspaper 23/4/2016, studies have shown that building motivation takes more energy that simply just doing the activity – so just do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.	Putting others/work/etc first and making excuses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself ‘what does this sabotaging behaviour cost me?’ What would you have, if you achieved your goal? What are all the things you could be doing if you weren’t making excuses and choosing to put yourself second? What do your family/friends really want for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What benefit do you get from not working on your goals? This may not be clear at first but there is always a payoff to the things we do, otherwise we wouldn’t do them – it may be a feeling of noble suffering/superiority/sacrifice etc but if we really asked the people in our lives whether they want us doing this, rather than working towards our goals, I think you know what they would say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.	Feeling oppressed by your goal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then change the goal. Break it down to small steps and make it achievable. Check – is it still what you want or have things changed? Do an assessment of your strengths and weaknesses to make sure you’re using strategies that exploit your strengths and minimise reliance on your weaknesses. Create a vision of what it will be like when you succeed that is bigger than your limitations/doubts/resistance and get into action- however small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.	Limiting beliefs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sabotage can often be caused by statements about the world or ourselves which we have accumulated over the years and believe to be true but which create self-imposed limits on what we think we can achieve in the world and who we are. These statements are often invisible to us– the people in our lives may be aware of them and that can be a place to start, however, working on limiting beliefs is central to the coaching process and provides a confidential space to explore these issues so that they no longer stop you from achieving your goals and creating a life that you love.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/04/28/are_you_sabotaging_yourself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/04/28/are_you_sabotaging_yourself/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are you trying to squeeze more into an already full life?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you trying to squeeze more into an already full life?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever noticed that so many things that could improve your life involve adding … &lt;strong&gt;more?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; time in the gym/with the kids/meditating/jogging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; information about getting fit/healthy eating/how to succeed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; attention to your loved ones/the present moment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; action around career goals/marketing yourself/searching for The One.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in my experience, trying to put more into a cup which is already full just results in overflow. In our lives that can feel like overwhelm - resulting in less sleep, poor health, low self esteem, guilt and even shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are led to believe that if we only knew/did/had/were … (fill in the gap yourself) our lives would be perfect, and when we fail and end up feeling worse about ourselves – and less likely to try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the job of a coach is to help you empty the cup – review your life to look at what’s working and, in areas of your life which aren’t working, examine what you have been doing and what you have learnt about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of emptying the cup also involves discarding the ‘shoulds’ in your life so that you are left with &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; core values – the ones that get you up in the morning. These values will be reflected in what you are committed to in life and the strengths that get you through the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching can act like a knife to cut away everything that isn’t &lt;u&gt;you&lt;/u&gt; or aligned with &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; values. Clients experience a clarity of vision that can be exhilarating, liberating the energy trapped in previous failed attempts, to be redirected into the strengths that have already got you this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;For example&lt;/u&gt;, who wants to lose weight? How many times have you tried and how much energy have you expended on this? However, to ‘lose weight’ covers many different areas- e.g. how healthy you feel, your size, what you eat, your shape.
What would it be like to give up the idea of losing weight? How would it feel to be ok about the weight you are now? Notice how your body responds to that thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, what is it &lt;u&gt;specifically&lt;/u&gt; that you want?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To feel toned/fit into a size smaller?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To feel less out of breath?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To sleep better?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To give up coffee/sugar/alcohol/chocolate/smoking?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To have more energy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Choose one area&lt;/u&gt; and look at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when you have tried and failed - and what you said about yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what you think you ‘should’ do/be/have in this area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you gave up all the regrets/blame/sense of failure, what one step could you do today to give you a positive result in this area?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make it something that you enjoy, something that you are already good at or something that is aligned to a commitment you already have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are filled to the brim with knowledge, but knowledge isn’t enough until it works in the service of &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; values, &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; strengths and &lt;u&gt;your&lt;/u&gt; commitments. 
Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/03/30/blog-march/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/03/30/blog-march/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coaching for carers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coaching is like a gym for the brain. It brings new perspective to a situation and supports people to find their own solutions and take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a previously full –time carer myself, I found that I had a lot of time to think, but felt that I couldn’t change anything about my situation. As a consequence, my thinking became more and more negative and brought me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation helped neither me nor the person I was caring for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend introduced me to coaching and I found that it opened the door to a new way of thinking. Coaching uses skilful questions to break up negative patterns of thinking, challenge assumptions and dispel the myths we tell ourselves  about ‘I can’t…..’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching focuses, not on the situation we are in, but on our perspective on that situation. When we explore our core values and find out what we are really committed to, then we re-discover the reasons why we are doing what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/IMG_1460.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ella&#39;s first image.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your top 3 values?&lt;/strong&gt; (Take out any values that you feel you ‘should’ have or you adopted because parents or an authority figure told you to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you express these values in your life? Who and what are you committed to? How do you measure your success? Is it in relation to your commitments or to other people’s expectations? What do you do that is not aligned to your values, and how much does this cost you in energy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How much energy would be available to you if you lived a life aligned with your values ? How would your view of your current life change if your perspective came from the values at the heart of who you are?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coaching doesn’t have to be about taking on the world, instead, it’s about creating a worldview centred on your values and creating a life that you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;Contacts page&lt;/a&gt; to sign up or to get in touch with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2016/01/17/coaching-for-carers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2016/01/17/coaching-for-carers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
